(843) 608-8743 www.AdamRCarroll.com

SUMMARY

Accomplished Computer Engineer with a strong background in both hardware and software in the technology industry. Possesses a broad range of experiences in the computer engineering, computer science, and academic fields. A dedicated and effective problem solver known for solving lengthy, complex problems without losing focus. A self-starter who is able to path-clear new projects or ideas with minimal guidance.

Technical Skills Include:

- C/C++
- Linux
- CPU Architecture
- System Validation
- Assembly Language (x86)

- Perl
- Agile / Scrum
- Git / Source Control
- Ruby on Rails
- HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

INTEL CORPORATION, Columbia, SC

2015 - Present

System Validation Engineer

Validated the correctness of the Intel Xeon processors. Analyzed system architectural documents and wrote Perl-based focus tests to validate against specific features and/or edge cases. Wrote and executed all focus tests required by the team's validation strategy. This required collaboration with teammates before authoring and running tests, as well as debugging all failures. Chaired weekly meetings with multiple international and other US Intel sites to coordinate the team's validation efforts.

- First employee in Columbia to implement the team's focus test tool (path clearing).
- Owner of the focus test tool and running all focus test content.
- Chairing weekly international meetings within the first year in this role.
- Authored a full test library to validate a Xeon-only feature set not covered by other tools.
- Completed extensive training via international travel and on-site exams.

360 QUOTE, LLC 2012 – 2015

Full-Stack Web Developer

Maintained and enhanced the company's fitness website, Exercise.com, using Ruby on Rails, CSS, and JavaScript. Worked on both the website's back-end for logic/computations and frontend for displaying the information in an understandable and appealing way. Managed Photoshop wireframe styling tasks, requiring significant attention to detail.

- Implemented site-wide standards for page design fonts, margins, colors, etc.
- Primary owner for all Photoshop wireframe work.
- Redesigned and implemented a new checkout system for online purchases.

Adam Carroll (843) 637-5012 Page 2 of 2

CLEMSON UNIVERSITY, Clemson, SC

2013 - 2015

Teaching Assistant

Taught 3 laboratory sessions a week of 12 students each for 4 semesters. Responsible for mastering all course material, effectively communicating the course material, ensuring student project completeness, and grading reports and tests.

- Taught and graded 6 lab sections for Microcontroller Interfacing (ECE 372).
- Taught and graded 6 lab sections for Computer Organization/x86 Assembly (ECE 273).
- Received consistently high ratings from students in lab competency, communication skills, and organization.

BOB JONES UNIVERSITY, Greenville, SC

2012 - 2013

Technology Assistant Crew Chief

Enforced computer lab rules and policies while helping students and faculty with computerrelated coursework and grading. Coordinated worker schedules, oversaw special shifts, and handled maintenance issues in the computer science labs.

- Trained and managed as many as 11 staff members.
- Promoted to Crew Chief after only 2 years with the company.

AAI CORPORATION (TEXTRON SYSTEMS), Goose Creek, SC

Summers 2010/2011

Software Engineering Intern

Developed test content for the DOD F-35 Joint Strike Fighter maintenance-training simulator. Tested the continuously evolving simulator environment for bugs. Researched terrain models as part of a TH-57 helicopter cockpit R&D simulator. Worked alongside the customer for on-site testing and analysis.

- Developed and tested F-35 maintenance training simulator lessons.
- Wrote task lists and technical documentation for training instructors.
- Researched terrain models for the TH-57 helicopter cockpit simulator.

EDUCATION

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Clemson University – Clemson, SC

May 2015 GPA: 4.00

Projects

- <u>Master's Thesis</u> Analyzed the effects of adding multimedia questions to a question/ answer website. This utilized the *MultiQuery* website and involved a 10-week user study.
- <u>MultiQuery</u> Designed and operated a website for a personalized question/answer social network (like Yahoo! Answers). The framework was Ruby on Rails with Bootstrap.
- Knock-Activated Door Opening Device Constructed and implemented a remote door opener that would open a door given a pre-programmed secret knock. All processing and logic was supplied by an Arduino Uno

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN ENGINEERING

Bob Jones University - Greenville, SC

May 2013 GPA: 3.86

Projects

 80Sim86 Simulator – Designed and wrote a learning simulator for Intel 8086 Assembly Language using C++ and Microsoft Visual Studio. The simulator was designed for teachers to enhance student learning and instruction for x86 Assembly.

Honors/Awards - Recipient of the BJU Outstanding Student in Physics and Engineering Award